Pronunciation.
Careful listeners will notice many subtle differences between the sounds of Tamil and those of English.
We concentrate here on features of pronunciation that are vital for clear understanding.
One very important distinction in the sounds of Tamil is that between long and short vowels.
In the Roman transcription we use, the long vowels are indicated by double letters.
So that you may hear and learn to make these distinctions, listen to and repeat the following pairs of words.
The word for 10.
பத்து (pattu)
The word for look.
பாரு (paaru)
The word for small.
சின்ன (sinna)
The word for fish.
மீன் (miin)
The word for salt.
உப்பு (uppu)
The word for town.
ஊரு (uuru)
The word for price.
விலை (vela)
The word for work.
வேலை (veela)
The word for one.
ஒரு (oru)
The word for run.
ஓடு (oodu)